Mohamed Elgazar

Sheikh Zayed, Egypt | melgazar725@gmail.com | 01010815084 | LinkedIn | Github

Objective

Mechatronics engineer with a focus on embedded software engineering and a strong technical background in programming languages such as C, C++, and Python. I am experienced in working with various microcontrollers and know how to interface with them effectively and I am also familiar with mobile development and web development.

Education

Mansoura University, Bachelor of Mechatronics Engineering

Sept 2020 - Sept 2024

- GPA: 3.4/4.0
- Coursework: Mechanics, Classic control, Embedded systems, Robotics, Linear algebra, Statistics, Artificial intelligence

Udacity - Egypt FWD, Embedded Systems Professional Nanodegree

Sept 2022 - Dec 2022

- Completed (Certificate)
- Coursework: Embedded Systems, AUTOSAR, Automotive, Automotive Communication protocols, Agaile, AVR and ARM microcontrollers

Udemy, Mastering RTOS and Embedded Linux | Mobile App Development with Flutter

Experience

Computer Science Instructor, Roboto Academy – Sheikh Zayed, Egypt

Oct 2024 - Present

- Designed and delivered robotics and computer science curricula
- Taught advanced programming and AI concepts to students
- Fostered a hands-on learning environment with robotics kits and software tools

Embedded Software Engineer Intern, Siemens – Eitesal – Egypt

June 2023 - Jan 2024

- Gained practical experience in microcontroller interfacing and communication protocols.
- Learned AUTOSAR software architecture and MISRA-C standards.
- Developed real-time firmware for ARM and AVR microcontrollers.
- Gained expertise in communication protocols such as SPI,I2C, and UART
- Experience with microcontroller-based systems and Real-Time Operating Systems

Projects

Advanced Exploration Robot

Github

- Developed a pipe exploration robot using the Raspberry Pi.
- Using Python to program the Raspberry Pi to collect data from sensors (Camera, Ultrasonic, etc.).
- Tools used: C++, Python, Raspberry Pi, NodeJs, STM32 MCU, Linux

AVR and ARM Drivers Github

- Write drivers code for peripherals such as GPIO, GPT, SPI, I2C, and ADC.
- Developed projects using ARM Cortex-M3 based STM32 microcontrollers.
- Tools Used: C, .C++, STM32CubeMX, XC8, Segger debugger

Technologies

Languages: C++, C, Python, Dart, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#

Technologies: Linux, RTOS, VS code, XCode, ARM, AVR, STM32Cube, Flutter, AUTOSAR, Git, Github